Andrew A Hamlin

aahamlin@gmail.com (860) 810 - 6538 https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewahamlin/

SUMMARY

An engineering leader who has built highly engaged teams that deliver substantial business value in enterprise software for over 20 years. An expert in optimizing software development processes, leveraging Agile-Lean methodologies, and developing distributed systems using on-premise, cloud and hybrid hosting models. Extensive leadership experience across the software dev lifecycle (SDLC), including release management, vendor management, partner integrations, recruitment and hiring, and workforce management of globally distributed teams.

I am a servant leader who values people over process, builds efficient workflows, promotes software craftsmanship, and am highly knowledgeable of service-oriented architecture (SOA), DevOps, data security & privacy, and globalization best practices.

Awarded the Employee Recognition Award for transforming Sustaining Engineering operations and raising Customer Satisfaction scores (as measured by KLAS).

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Management of end-to-end product lifecycle with SDLCs: Agile, Kanban, SAFe
- Effective communication at executive levels
- Data-driven continuous improvement; based on Key Performance Indicators (KPIs)
- Investment in continuous learning; constantly exploring and applying new skills and technology, and providing safety for people to fail, learn, grow, and innovate
- Recruitment of engineers consistently recognized for their skill, talent and humility
- Passionate and driven to build customer-focused teams and products

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr Software Development Manager Gerber Technology, LLC 2018 - present

Strategically attacked product quality and maintenance costs resulting in 86% decrease in customer defects by negotiating a balance of feature/defects/technical debt across CAD roadmap and championing code reviews and teamwork. Greatly reduced "commit to acceptance" cycle time by 81.5% through data-driven analysis and workflow changes. Mentored engineering, product management and executives in Agile release planning and metrics. Provided expertise toward hybrid-cloud digital transformation including AWS solutions & REST API design. Directly managed 20 resources: 8 onshore and 12 offshore contract resources.

Andrew A Hamlin

Software Development Manager

Sailpoint Technologies

2017 - 2018

Led teams developing an enterprise governance platform including REST & SCIM APIs, OAuth 2.0, Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA), Cloud integrations (AWS, Dropbox), Localization & Accessibility (Section 508, WCAG2). Scrum mastered 2 full-stack teams. Engaged teams in design/code reviews (Java, AngularJS) that guided product, architecture and career growth (tech and soft skills). Optimized end-to-end process with localization partner. Hiring manager; 8 directs, 3 new hires.

Software Development Manager/Team Lead Caradigm USA, LLC

2013 - 2016

End-to-end management of 2 on-time product launches. Achieved 70% code coverage including unit & integration testing of REST APIs & data warehouse in an automated build-deploy-test workflow. Led full-stack teams developing Single-page App (SPA) in JavaScript (Knockout.js), REST APIs in Java & C#, badge reader integration SDK in Python & Java, stored procedures in SQL server and SSIS. Developed interview playbook; hired database & front-end engineers.

Sustaining Engineering Manager

Caradigm USA, LLC

2012 - 2013

Drove 6 month turn-around of Sustaining Engineering operations; received *Employee Recognition Award*. Established real-time dashboard, KPIs and company-wide service-level agreements (SLA). Managed one onshore & six offshore contract resources. Raised customer satisfaction scores measured by KLAS by establishing a cross-department triage process and achieved 100% SLAs.

Software Development Engineer II

Microsoft Corporation

2010 - 2012

Led transition between languages and technology stacks (C#/.NET, Windows). Design and implementation of PowerShell API to administer Linux server clusters. Advocated adoption of software architectures (Azure, Hyper-V) and libraries that improved performance & reliability, and increased testability of service layers (SOA, WCF). Codeveloped MSBuild customizations to support Java & OSS software builds.

Senior Software Engineer

Sentillion, Inc

1999 - 2010

Developed enterprise IAM solution for Healthcare; a *KLAS Top 20* product. Direct customer support in startup environment. Introduced innovative OSS solutions for web administration, eliminated \$1K/server licensing & slashed fulfillment costs.

EDUCATION

B.S. Management and Information Technology

Daniel Webster College Nashua, NH